<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Organisation | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/organisation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-20T15:28:10+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Home Assistant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explaining the Updater]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/10/25/explaining-the-updater/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-25T04:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/10/25/explaining-the-updater</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[On Saturday, we released [Home Assistant 0.31][0.31] which includes an improved updater component that checks for new versions using the Home Assistant servers. We wanted to update the community on its rollout and answer some questions that have come up. As part of the update check anonymous information about your operating system and Python version is submitted to Home Assistant servers unless you have opted out.

## <a class='title-link' name='why-we-changed-the-updater' href='#why-we-changed-the-updater'></a> Why we changed the updater 
This change was driven by two important factors.

### <a class='title-link' name='improving-the-security-of-the-users' href='#improving-the-security-of-the-users'></a> Improving the security of the users. 

As a user, you will be able to be notified if you are running a Home Assistant version that includes components that have known security flaws.

Although we hope to not have to use this feature often, it is important for us to be able to reach out to impacted users. We had the need for such a feature once in the past. Due to a bug the forecast.io sensor was making a huge amount of API requests causing some of our users to get charged because they went over the free quota.

Please note that this functionality is not done yet but will be available in a future release.

### <a class='title-link' name='focusing-our-resources-where-it-matters' href='#focusing-our-resources-where-it-matters'></a> Focusing our resources where it matters 

As developers of Home Assistant, we will be able to see in what kind of environments Home Assistant is running. Here’s a few data points we didn’t have until now:

* Total number of instances
* Which operating systems versions and flavors are in use
* Python version
* What option is more popular: Docker, Virtualenv or bare metal installs?
* How popular is our new [Raspberry Pi image][rpi-image]?


## <a class='title-link' name='why-we-look-up-your-ip-address-with-geoip' href='#why-we-look-up-your-ip-address-with-geoip'></a> Why we look up your IP address with GeoIP 
We store the city so that we can see where our users are from. This information will be used to give us a better insight in where our users are from. This will help us gather data to see if we should for example prioritize internationalization. In addition, we previously had a nasty bug with the `sun` component in which users above a certain latitude were having crashes multiple times a day. Had the updater component been in place we could have targeted a special priority update notification only to them.

As stated in the release blog post, the location information is _not_ provided by your local Home Assistant installation but is instead gathered by comparing your IP address against the [GeoLite2 data created by MaxMind][geolite]. From their documentation:

> IP geolocation is inherently imprecise. Locations are often near the center of the population. Any location provided by a GeoIP database should not be used to identify a particular address or household.

## <a class='title-link' name='why-is-it-enabled-by-default' href='#why-is-it-enabled-by-default'></a> Why is it enabled by default 
We decided to have it enabled by default because we consider the information that is gathered not harmful. We understand that not everyone will agree with us and so we have provided [multiple ways to opt out][opt-out].

It is in our short-term planning to add an option to control this to our frontend.

## <a class='title-link' name='source-code' href='#source-code'></a> Source Code 
The source code of our updater AWS Lambda function is now available [here][source].


[0.31]: /blog/2016/10/22/flash-briefing-updater-hacktoberfest/#comment-2965607849
[geolite]: https://dev.maxmind.com/geoip/geoip2/geolite2/
[opt-out]: /components/updater/
[rpi-image]: /blog/2016/10/01/we-have-raspberry-image-now/
[source]: https://github.com/home-assistant/Analytics-Receiver
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[To Infinity and Beyond 🚀]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/04/19/to-infinity-and-beyond/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T05:44:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/04/19/to-infinity-and-beyond</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[After 2.5 years I think we can proudly say: Home Assistant is a success. I write _we_ because Home Assistant is no longer a one-person side project. It has become the side project of many people who spend countless hours on making Home Assistant the best home automation software out there. To acknowledge this we migrated the repositories from being under my name to be under our own [organisation on GitHub][gh-ha].

On our journey we've reached many noteworthy milestones:

 - #1 on HackerNews
 - Featured on ProductHunt
 - Trending repository on GitHub
 - 3000 stars on GitHub
 - 1.5 million page views on our website
 - Speaker at OpenIoT Summit 2016

All these accomplishments are a nice pat on the back but our journey is far from over. There are a lot of challenges ahead if we want to become the go to solution for home automation _for everyone_.

Until now the focus has been on making a platform that developers love to use. A platform that is simple but customizable. A platform that is both powerful and reliable. But most important: a platform that is local and open. Home Assistant does a great job at all these things.

There will be some major challenges ahead of us to target groups other than developers. Easy installation and easy configuration being the #1. I'm sure that we'll be able to eventually achieve these goals. I can't say yet how or when. As with everything Home Assistant, we'll take tiny steps, gathering feedback along the way to make sure we're solving the right problems.

I am confident that we will get there because we are set up for success: we have a robust architecture, high test coverage and an active community of world class developers and users. On top of that, we use Python which allows us to move fast and tackle complex problems in elegant ways. It is so easy to learn that it allows any programmer, experienced or not, to contribute support for devices and services. It's as simple as [filling in the blanks].

I would like to put out a big thank you to all our contributors who make Home Assistant what it is today. It doesn't matter if it is form of code, documentation or giving support in our [chat room] or [forums]. You. all. rock.

Cheers to the future!

Paulus

[gh-ha]: https://github.com/home-assistant/
[filling in the blanks]: /developers/platform_example_sensor/#code
[chat room]: https://gitter.im/home-assistant/home-assistant
[forums]: https://community.home-assistant.io/
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New logo for Home Assistant]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/08/new-logo/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-08T22:16:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/08/new-logo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[It is well known that you are either a good programmer or a good designer. It's rare you'll meet someone that is both. That's why it wasn't surprising to anyone that the logo that I made was mediocre &mdash; at best. Luckily, [Jeremy Geltman](http://jeremygeltman.com/) has come to the rescue and contributed a brand new logo for Home Assistant.

The new logo follows Googles material design spec. It uses the blue color that Home Assistant uses in the interface and it comes in two versions: a high detailed version (for homescreen icon etc) and a simple version (for favicon etc).

<p class='img'>
<img src='/images/blog/ha-logo-history.png' />
The old logo, the new detailed logo and the new simple logo.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
