<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Organisation | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/organisation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-16T16:00:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Home Assistant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[To Infinity and Beyond 🚀]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/04/19/to-infinity-and-beyond/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T05:44:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2016/04/19/to-infinity-and-beyond</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[After 2.5 years I think we can proudly say: Home Assistant is a success. I write _we_ because Home Assistant is no longer a one-person side project. It has become the side project of many people who spend countless hours on making Home Assistant the best home automation software out there. To acknowledge this we migrated the repositories from being under my name to be under our own [organisation on GitHub][gh-ha].

On our journey we've reached many noteworthy milestones:

 - #1 on HackerNews
 - Featured on ProductHunt
 - Trending repository on GitHub
 - 3000 stars on GitHub
 - 1.5 million page views on our website
 - Speaker at OpenIoT Summit 2016

All these accomplishments are a nice pat on the back but our journey is far from over. There are a lot of challenges ahead if we want to become the go to solution for home automation _for everyone_.

Until now the focus has been on making a platform that developers love to use. A platform that is simple but customizable. A platform that is both powerful and reliable. But most important: a platform that is local and open. Home Assistant does a great job at all these things.

There will be some major challenges ahead of us to target groups other than developers. Easy installation and easy configuration being the #1. I'm sure that we'll be able to eventually achieve these goals. I can't say yet how or when. As with everything Home Assistant, we'll take tiny steps, gathering feedback along the way to make sure we're solving the right problems.

I am confident that we will get there because we are set up for success: we have a robust architecture, high test coverage and an active community of world class developers and users. On top of that, we use Python which allows us to move fast and tackle complex problems in elegant ways. It is so easy to learn that it allows any programmer, experienced or not, to contribute support for devices and services. It's as simple as [filling in the blanks].

I would like to put out a big thank you to all our contributors who make Home Assistant what it is today. It doesn't matter if it is form of code, documentation or giving support in our [chat room] or [forums]. You. all. rock.

Cheers to the future!

Paulus

[gh-ha]: https://github.com/home-assistant/
[filling in the blanks]: /developers/platform_example_sensor/#code
[chat room]: https://gitter.im/home-assistant/home-assistant
[forums]: https://community.home-assistant.io/
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New logo for Home Assistant]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/08/new-logo/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-08T22:16:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/08/new-logo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[It is well known that you are either a good programmer or a good designer. It's rare you'll meet someone that is both. That's why it wasn't surprising to anyone that the logo that I made was mediocre &mdash; at best. Luckily, [Jeremy Geltman](http://jeremygeltman.com/) has come to the rescue and contributed a brand new logo for Home Assistant.

The new logo follows Googles material design spec. It uses the blue color that Home Assistant uses in the interface and it comes in two versions: a high detailed version (for homescreen icon etc) and a simple version (for favicon etc).

<p class='img'>
<img src='/images/blog/ha-logo-history.png' />
The old logo, the new detailed logo and the new simple logo.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
