<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Announcements | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-20T08:39:56+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Home Assistant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A frank and serious warning about Senic COVI]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2017/06/20/things-you-should-know-about-senic-covi/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-20T01:04:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2017/06/20/things-you-should-know-about-senic-covi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class='note'>
TL;DR: We are not affiliated with Senic or their COVI product. We will not support their users and you will get a subpar Home Assistant experience by using their product. **Furthermore, we cannot guarantee stability or security if you use Senic products.**
</p>

Recently Home Assistant has been made aware of a product by [Senic] that will be launching later today on [Kickstarter][kickstarter] ([screenshot][ks-backup]). Senic is not new in the IoT business, we have had support for their first product ([Nuimo]) since last September. Their new product, COVI, uses Home Assistant as its core home automation codebase. This is great, that is what open source is all about. However, they also use our name and logo in their Kickstarter, with the press and in their [developer documentation] ([screenshot][docs-backup]) to give the appearance of being affiliated with Home Assistant, against our wishes. Which is not great, at all.

Take some of the following quotes from their Kickstarter campaign:

> COVI is built on an open source platform. The Senic team, along with outside developers, contributes to this platform to create the integrations for COVI.

> With COVI, we have built upon an open platform called Home Assistant that anyone can contribute to alongside our engineers and the Home Assistant community.

Although those quotes are technically correct, they are very misleading. The Senic team contributes only to their own platform, they have not contributed to Home Assistant, its integrations or related projects. We did receive [1 contribution][netdisco-contrib] from them for [Netdisco], our network discovery package. It included a memory leak and required us to publish [a hotfix release][hotfix] for the 0.39 series. Their contribution has since been reverted. A third party contributor had contributed support for their Nuimo controller.

Here is a quote that their CEO Tobias Eichenwald gave [to Forbes]:

> Unlike many larger companies who build closed automation platforms, COVI is built on an open source platform called Home Assistant that includes 500+ contributors. This allows COVI to be integrated into any ecosystem or platform with an open API.

They reached out to us on April 7 ([screenshot][email-backup]). We replied on April 11 and told them they should not use our name as we do not want to be affiliated with them because we do not want to support their users. After that one e-mail we had never heard from them again until Forbes accidentally published an article about it before the Kickstarter launched. We did not get any chance to give feedback on their Kickstarter campaign content and they went ahead and used our name and logo without authorization or permission.

If you want an open source and constantly evolving product, get yourself a $35 Raspberry Pi, install our hub [Hass.io] for free and buy yourself some cheap and reliable [IKEA Trådfri lights][tradfri] to get yourself a basic home automation setup. If you want a $250 talking lamp, go buy the COVI. Just know that we are not affiliated with Senic, we will not support their users and you will get a subpar Home Assistant experience by using their product. **Furthermore, we cannot guarantee stability or security if you use Senic products.**

Senic, we know that this is probably not what you wanted to wake up to on the first day of your Kickstarter but you left us no choice. Please reach out to us to help make this right. **We will always do everything in our power to protect the best interests of the Home Assistant community, <span style='text-decoration: underline;'>our</span> 500+ contributors and 250,000+ users.** If we don't hear from you by Wednesday, June 21st, we will be forced to consider further actions.

Sincerely,

**Paulus Schoutsen**<br>
Founder, Home Assistant

**Robbie Trencheny**<br>
Core Developer, Home Assistant

[Senic]: https://www.senic.com/en/
[kickstarter]: https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/802159142/1793705123?token=03dc08b4#
[ks-backup]: /images/blog/2017-06-senic-covi/covi-kickstarter-screenshot.png
[email-backup]: /images/blog/2017-06-senic-covi/email-senic.png
[docs-backup]: /images/blog/2017-06-senic-covi/senic-docs-screenshot.png
[Netdisco]: https://github.com/home-assistant/netdisco
[netdisco-contrib]: https://github.com/home-assistant/netdisco/pull/94
[hotfix]: /blog/2017/02/25/config-panel-and-state-restoration/#release-0392---march-1
[Hass.io]: /hassio/
[to Forbes]: https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:https://www.forbes.com/sites/paularmstrongtech/2017/06/19/covi-is-about-to-make-some-general-electric-execs-very-unhappy/
[tradfri]: /blog/2017/04/17/ikea-tradfri-internet-of-things-done-right/
[Nuimo]: /components/nuimo_controller/
[developer documentation]: http://blog.senic.com/posts/the-senic-hub-a-brief-software-overview
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[1 year and 22 days ago I had an idea...]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2017/04/15/ios/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-15T08:04:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2017/04/15/ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[1 year and 22 days ago, or 387 days ago, on March 25th, 2016, I started a project to bring Home Assistant to the iPhone.

I thought the existing notification and location solutions were lacking in one way or another and had wanted for _years_ to have a project I could call my own which would allow me to learn iOS development. What better way then implementing an extremely complex application like Home Assistant?

I started with a lot of steam. I remember cranking out the initial work that night and showing Paulus who was astounded at how fast the UI was coming together.

Little would I know how many problems I would create and uncover throughout the process. Writing a mobile app for a project that moves as fast as Home Assistant is... tricky, to say the least. In the time since I started writing the app, Home Assistant had 90 releases. I started writing the day before 0.16 was released. Now we are at 0.42.3. Time flies...

I couldn't have completed the app without help and input from the community. By the end I had 700 beta testers, of which about 500 were very active in testing the app.

I received emails and forum posts almost every day, even when the app would go without an update for weeks and sometimes months at a time as my life got busier and busier.

I wanted this app to be done 9 months ago, at least, but my drive to add more and more features killed that idea. This really taught me the value of the MVP over the kitchen sink.

It may not look the way that I wanted it to initially, with beautiful native UI components, but thats okay. What I really cared about is there. The notification and location engines are some of the most customizable and powerful available in an iOS app if I do say so myself. I made them this way to keep with the spirit of infinite flexibility that is enshrined in Home Assistant.

Just because the app is released doesn't mean we are at the end of the road. It's only the beginning. There's plenty of bugs to fix still, improvements to make, features to add. Beta testing will continue, and if anything, be expanded. I do want to have a native UI someday, but that's pretty hard with how fast the project moves.

The biggest request I have is for more developers on the project. As many of you know, I have my hands in many different parts of Home Assistant, from governance and organization to managing the forums to writing this app, managing the Homebridge plugin and even sometimes writing code for the actual core codebase! I can't do it all, and I'm still a new iOS developer who doesn't know all the best practices.

The app is [open source](https://github.com/home-assistant/home-assistant-iOS), has been for the last few months when I first prepared to submit it to Apple for review. I invite Swift developers to come and join me in building it. Trust me, there's tons to do.

**1 year and 22 days ago, on March 25th, 2016 I began work on Home Assistant for iOS.**

**Today, April 16th, 2017, I am _extremely_ excited to announce that Home Assistant for iOS has been approved by Apple and is now available to download for ~~a monthly subscription starting at $9.99~~ free! (had to get a joke in here somewhere!) on the iOS App Store in every country.**

<p style="text-align: center;"><a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/home-assistant-open-source-home-automation/id1099568401?mt=8" style="display:inline-block;overflow:hidden;background:url(//linkmaker.itunes.apple.com/assets/shared/badges/en-us/appstore-lrg.svg) no-repeat;width:135px;height:40px;background-size:contain;"></a></p>

_Please note, you must have Home Assistant 0.42.4 or later installed for the app to function properly._

Thanks for everything so far, I'm looking forward to the road that lies ahead for Home Assistant on iOS!

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
